<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Clinics on World Bank Data Lab</title><link>/workshop_types/clinics/</link><description>Recent content in Clinics on World Bank Data Lab</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 08:45:14 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/workshop_types/clinics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>COVID 19 Clinic: Food Security</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/covid-19-clinic-food-security/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 08:45:14 -0400</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/covid-19-clinic-food-security/</guid><description>COVID-19 and the on-going locust plague pose high risks to food security. Colleagues from the Agriculture Global Practice ask, &amp;ldquo;What are the available data and digital tools with potential to monitor food prices and help mitigate food supply chain disruptions?&amp;rdquo; Speakers from the IMF, FAO, the IFC, Premise, and Indigo share their resources and ideas to help address this challenge.</description></item><item><title>COVID 19 Clinic: Location Based Indicators</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/covid-19-clinic-location-based-indicators/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 08:40:57 -0400</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/covid-19-clinic-location-based-indicators/</guid><description>Health colleagues asked the Lab to organize an &amp;ldquo;emergency&amp;rdquo; clinic to help them narrow down a set of indicators to support social distancing policy formulation. To get started, we invited external partners from Google, Facebook, MapBox, Unacast, and Carto to share the latest progress globally, as well as colleagues from DEC, GFDRR, Poverty, and FCVs to share progress on the Bank’s efforts. With this firehose of a session, we herded cats to mitigate duplication of effort and set a foundation for collaboration.</description></item><item><title>COVID 19 Clinic: Air Quality</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/covid-19-clinic-air-quality/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 08:38:45 -0400</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/covid-19-clinic-air-quality/</guid><description>At the request of our FCV colleagues, the Lab organized a clinic on the link between air quality and COVID-19 outcomes. We invited speakers from the Environment GP, the European Space Agency, and Climacell to share resources and best practices.</description></item><item><title>COVID 19 Clinic: Mobility Data</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/covid-19-clinic-mobility-data/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 08:37:10 -0400</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/covid-19-clinic-mobility-data/</guid><description>The Lab organized a Data Clinic for our DIME colleagues, to discuss on-going and proposed use of mobile device data for COVID-19 analytics. Guest speakers include colleagues from Cuebiq and Flowminder, as well as Bank staff sharing ideas and new initiatives.</description></item><item><title>Covid 19 Clinic Health GP Priorities and Big Data</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/covid-19-clinic-health-gp-priorities-and-big-data/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 08:28:53 -0400</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/covid-19-clinic-health-gp-priorities-and-big-data/</guid><description>The Lab organized a Data Clinic with our Health GP colleagues and Lab memebrs to learn about: (1) WB Health GP priorities for addressing COVID-19 and planned analytical work; (2) Data resources available to Bank staff through the Development Data Partnership (Facebook, Google Health Trends, and MapBox); and (3) Preliminary big data analytics being undertaken by Bank colleagues on different aspects of COVID-19 response.</description></item><item><title>Locust Crisis 2020</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/locust-crisis-2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 08:04:46 -0400</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/locust-crisis-2020/</guid><description>The Lab organized a Data Clinic (first of its kind) with our Agriculture GP colleagues to brainstorm ideas for tracking and predicting locust swarms, drawing upon the many data resources we have in the Bank. In addition to our Agriculture GP colleagues, colleagues from Climate Change GP, Environment GP, FCV GP, ITS GeoLab, Geospatial Operations and Support Team, DEC Analytics and Tools, DEC Development Data Hub, Development Data Partnership, and WBG Library joined us at the clinic.</description></item></channel></rss>