<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tech Talks on World Bank Data Lab</title><link>/workshop_types/tech-talks/</link><description>Recent content in Tech Talks on World Bank Data Lab</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 18:52:13 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/workshop_types/tech-talks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fun Toys and Serious Tools for Field Data Collection</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/fun-toys-and-serious-tools-for-field-data-collection/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 18:52:13 -0400</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/fun-toys-and-serious-tools-for-field-data-collection/</guid><description>Spice up your next mission with modern data collection methods. First, learn how to capture street view images(spoiler alert - it&amp;rsquo;s easy) and then how to use these images to support project monitoring (even in FCVs), RAP development, DRM risk assessments, road safety assessments, and more. Then, learn how your colleagues are training clients to collect geo-tagged data for project monitoring. The session will wrap up with a show-and-tell table, with a selection of data collection tools and apps you can try (sub-text: come in person - it&amp;rsquo;ll be informative + fun)!</description></item><item><title>An Economist, Data Sicentist, and Geographer Walk Iinto a Bar...</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/an-economist-data-sicentist-and-geographer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 18:30:32 -0400</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/an-economist-data-sicentist-and-geographer/</guid><description>You&amp;rsquo;re almost out of BB, and your project&amp;rsquo;s gotta move. You need analytical support, but can only afford one person &amp;ndash; do you choose the experienced economist, the hotshot data scientist, or the savvy geospatial specialist? What is the difference, anyway? Come find out in this friendly smackdown, where colleagues show off their professional pride as they tackle the same development challenge from different perspectives. Be prepared for the surprise ending.</description></item><item><title>Your Brain Is Not Enough. Use Modern Data</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/your-brain-is-not-enough-use-modern-data/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 18:50:15 -0400</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/your-brain-is-not-enough-use-modern-data/</guid><description>You&amp;rsquo;ve heard about big data and AI. Now be empowered to use them. How? Find out in this engaging Tech Talk, where you will participate in a live BOT or NOT Turing test, followed by discussions with Kalev Leetrau (RealClear Media Group), who created the world’s largest open news database (GDELT), and Joe Flasher (Amazon Web Services), who will introduce the Amazon Sustainable Data Program &amp;ndash; an unprecedented collection of open data directly relevant to Bank work.</description></item><item><title>Need Data? Start Here (Not There)</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/need-data-start-here-not-there/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 18:26:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/need-data-start-here-not-there/</guid><description>Every World Bank project begins with data, but not every project takes advantage of the open and proprietary data sources available to all staff. Learn how to level up your project data acquisition strategy in this lightning talk + game show mash-up.</description></item><item><title>Data Is Dead. Long Live Data.</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/data-is-dead-long-live-data/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 16:49:58 -0400</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/data-is-dead-long-live-data/</guid><description>The use of data to design and monitor Bank operations isn&amp;rsquo;t new, but technologies are quickly transforming the efficiency and efficacy of our data practices, as well as the risks. No staff or client should be left behind &amp;ndash; join our inaugural interactive Tech Talk to find out what we need to know, how we&amp;rsquo;ll learn, and, critically, how we will be supported through the revolution.</description></item></channel></rss>