<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Workshops on World Bank Data Lab</title><link>https://wb-data-lab.netlify.app/workshop_types/workshops/</link><description>Recent content in Workshops on World Bank Data Lab</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 07:31:44 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wb-data-lab.netlify.app/workshop_types/workshops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Data Partner Workshop Climacell</title><link>https://wb-data-lab.netlify.app/workshops-and-clinics/data-partner-workshop-climacell/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 07:31:44 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wb-data-lab.netlify.app/workshops-and-clinics/data-partner-workshop-climacell/</guid><description>Climacell combines traditional weather sensor data with non-traditional sources to derive up-to-the minute, real time micro weather and air quality mapping and forecasts. There service is used primarily by utilities and transportation companies, like Uber and Ford, and airlines, such as JetBlue, United, and Delta. The workshop focused on the Bank&amp;rsquo;s response to the locust crisis in east Africa as a case study, but discussion and questions covered all manner of challenges &amp;ndash; transport, agriculture, industry, etc.</description></item><item><title>Esa Earth Observation Clinic</title><link>https://wb-data-lab.netlify.app/workshops-and-clinics/esa-earth-observation-clinic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 19:30:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wb-data-lab.netlify.app/workshops-and-clinics/esa-earth-observation-clinic/</guid><description>The European Space Agency (ESA) supports on-call, prequalified geospatial firms ready to support your project on all manner of satellite-imagery and remote sensing activities. Support, valued at &amp;lt;= US$45,000, will be provided to qualified applicants. Apply through the Development Data Partnership (datapartnership.org).</description></item><item><title>Center for Open Science</title><link>https://wb-data-lab.netlify.app/workshops-and-clinics/center-for-open-science/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 19:30:10 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wb-data-lab.netlify.app/workshops-and-clinics/center-for-open-science/</guid><description>Dr. Soderberg discussed the challenges and opportunities of Open Science and how the Center for Open Science is providing training and guidance to organizations on data sharing/reuse, and adding rigor to data analysis.</description></item><item><title>GIS and COVID-19: How Mapping Supports Response and Recovery</title><link>https://wb-data-lab.netlify.app/workshops-and-clinics/gis-and-covid19-how-mapping-supports-response-and-recovery/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 18:50:15 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wb-data-lab.netlify.app/workshops-and-clinics/gis-and-covid19-how-mapping-supports-response-and-recovery/</guid><description>In this evelopment Data Partnership event, participants learn how IDB, UNICEF, and the WHO are using ESRI GIS technology to supporting COVID-19 response and recovery.</description></item><item><title>Learn How to Use Twitter Data In Bank Projects</title><link>https://wb-data-lab.netlify.app/workshops-and-clinics/learn-how-to-use-twitter-data-in-bank-projects/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 18:50:15 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wb-data-lab.netlify.app/workshops-and-clinics/learn-how-to-use-twitter-data-in-bank-projects/</guid><description>Through the Development Data Partnership, World Bank staff have free access to Twitter’s Enterprise API platform, which offers real-time and historical social data. During this workshop, Twitter staff helped staff get started.</description></item><item><title>Facebook Data for Good Workshop</title><link>https://wb-data-lab.netlify.app/workshops-and-clinics/facebook-data-for-good-workshop/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 14:44:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wb-data-lab.netlify.app/workshops-and-clinics/facebook-data-for-good-workshop/</guid><description>Through the Development Data Partnership with Facebook, staff can now access anonymized Facebook data products. Facebook colleagues introduced these new resources, and staff who have been using them presented their work on gender, energy, and disaster risk management projects.</description></item><item><title>Mapping and Analyzing Geospatial Data for Social Assistance Delivery</title><link>https://wb-data-lab.netlify.app/workshops-and-clinics/mapping-and-analyzing-geospatial-data-for-social-assistance-delivery/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 08:02:13 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wb-data-lab.netlify.app/workshops-and-clinics/mapping-and-analyzing-geospatial-data-for-social-assistance-delivery/</guid><description>Learn how the team used geospatial data to improve the delivery of social assistance programs in Tunisia. The event is jointly organized by Social Protection &amp;amp; Jobs Global Practice, ITS Technology and Innovation Lab, and the WB Data Lab as part of the LearnDTech Initiative.</description></item><item><title>Measuring Equitable Access to Health Facilities with Data Partnerships and Open-Source Tools</title><link>https://wb-data-lab.netlify.app/workshops-and-clinics/measuring-equitable-access-to-health-facilities/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 08:00:22 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wb-data-lab.netlify.app/workshops-and-clinics/measuring-equitable-access-to-health-facilities/</guid><description>Meet our summer intern Afeefah Khazi-Syed, biological engineering major at MIT, as she presents her research on analyzing physical access to health facilities. She hopes her work can inform decisions on how to allocate scarce resources towards placement of mobile health services. Afeefah&amp;rsquo;s work, which includes open-source code that Bank staff can use to replicate her results, utilizes data from Facebook and MapBox, acquired through the Development Data Partnership (datapartnership.org).</description></item><item><title>Data Science Talk: Learn How to Use Crowdsourced Smartphone GPS Data on your Project</title><link>https://wb-data-lab.netlify.app/workshops-and-clinics/data-science-talk-learn-how-to-use-crowdsourced-smartphone-gps-data/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 07:57:33 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wb-data-lab.netlify.app/workshops-and-clinics/data-science-talk-learn-how-to-use-crowdsourced-smartphone-gps-data/</guid><description>The Development Data Partnership has partnered with four mobility data providers to acquire smartphone GPS data across many emerging economies. These data have applications for understanding population movement during the pandemic, supporting client advisory on topics such as social distancing measures, placement of mobilie testing facilities, and estimating economic activity. At the workshop, participants learned about these data providers, the data transformations undertaken by the Partnership team to make analytics easier, the data documentation system, and recent work on COVID-19 indicators.</description></item><item><title>Data Science Talk: Using Social Media Online News and Text Analysis for Monitoring COVID-19 Impacts</title><link>https://wb-data-lab.netlify.app/workshops-and-clinics/data-science-talk-using-social-media-online-news-and-text-analysis/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 19:38:43 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wb-data-lab.netlify.app/workshops-and-clinics/data-science-talk-using-social-media-online-news-and-text-analysis/</guid><description>A Social Development GP team used alternative data (Twitter, Instagram, news media, Facebook, Google, Premise, etc.) to boost their COVID-19 social impact monitoring. Their work helped rapidly inform decision makers and identify rising public concerns, with a large population sample at a very low cost. Talk topics includesed: monitoring conversations via social media and online news; crowdsourcing citizen information via online surveys; comparing results across different data collection efforts; and integrating with other big data efforts, such as mobility analytics.</description></item><item><title>Data Science Talk: Monitoring Sentiment Towards COVID 19 Policies Using GDELT</title><link>https://wb-data-lab.netlify.app/workshops-and-clinics/data-science-talk-monitoring-sentiment-towards-covid-19-policies-using-gdelt/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 19:30:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wb-data-lab.netlify.app/workshops-and-clinics/data-science-talk-monitoring-sentiment-towards-covid-19-policies-using-gdelt/</guid><description>GDELT, an open-licesne repository of real time local news data, is being used to track sentiment towards COVID-19 policies and challenges. The program&amp;rsquo;s founder, Kalev Leetrau, introduces how to access the many resources avaialble through the platform.</description></item><item><title>Data Partner Workshop: Ookla</title><link>https://wb-data-lab.netlify.app/workshops-and-clinics/data-partner-workshop-ookla/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 19:36:58 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wb-data-lab.netlify.app/workshops-and-clinics/data-partner-workshop-ookla/</guid><description>Ookla, part of the Development Data Partnership, is one of the world&amp;rsquo;s largest providers of global Internet connectivity intelligence data. The workshop started with an introduction to the Ookla platofrm and was followed by a clinic with three Bank team who had submitted proposals to work with Ookla data.</description></item><item><title>Data Partner Workshop: Indigo</title><link>https://wb-data-lab.netlify.app/workshops-and-clinics/data-partner-workshop-indigo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 19:30:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wb-data-lab.netlify.app/workshops-and-clinics/data-partner-workshop-indigo/</guid><description>We are very excited to introduce our newest Development Data Partnership member, Indigo. Through Indigo&amp;rsquo;s Atlas platform, users can access high-resolution, real-time data on crop location and health, impact of weather on crops, and more. During this introductory workshop, we learned about and discussed how we can make the most of this new platform.</description></item><item><title>US Digital Service Field Trip</title><link>https://wb-data-lab.netlify.app/workshops-and-clinics/us-digital-service-field-trip/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 07:18:57 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wb-data-lab.netlify.app/workshops-and-clinics/us-digital-service-field-trip/</guid><description>Staff were treated to a presentation on how US federal government attracts talented mid-career tech talent to do a &amp;ldquo;tour of service&amp;rdquo; to help modernize public services, followed by a visit to the US Digital Service office, across from the White House.</description></item><item><title>Amazon Web Services Training</title><link>https://wb-data-lab.netlify.app/workshops-and-clinics/amazon-web-services/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 13:03:56 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wb-data-lab.netlify.app/workshops-and-clinics/amazon-web-services/</guid><description>Amazon Web Services (AWS) training is part of a series of events organized by Development Data Partnership for IT staff and data scientists. The course covered new Amazon tools to make it easier and faster to organize and analyze very large, unstructured data. Training materials include self-paced, step-by-step hands-on lab activities. To access lab materials, please request permission from datalab@worldbank.org to access via GitHub.</description></item></channel></rss>