<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Workshops on World Bank Data Lab</title><link>/workshop_types/workshops/</link><description>Recent content in Workshops on World Bank Data Lab</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 04:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/workshop_types/workshops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mapillary: How Can Street-Level Imagery and Maps Be Leveraged In Climate Change Related Projects?</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/mapillary-how-can-street-level-imagery-and-maps-be-leveraged-in-climate-change-related-projects/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/mapillary-how-can-street-level-imagery-and-maps-be-leveraged-in-climate-change-related-projects/</guid><description>In this session, Edoardo Neerhut and Christopher Beddow from Meta shared Mapillary&amp;rsquo;s products and image datasets, and use cases for improving urban mobility, monitoring flooding, and surveys post-cyclones/hurricanes and bushfires/wildfires, among others.</description></item><item><title>What Do People Think About Climate Change? Meta's Climate Change</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/what-do-people-think-about-climate-change-meta-s-climate-change/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/what-do-people-think-about-climate-change-meta-s-climate-change/</guid><description>In this session, Meta&amp;rsquo;s Data For Good team presented the Climate Change Opinion Survey - a survey that explores public climate change knowledge, attitudes, policy preferences, and behaviors across different countries.
The team also discussed Meta&amp;rsquo;s Climate Conversations Maps and other climate-related datasets.</description></item><item><title>SpaceX: How Starlink Broadband From Space Is Equalizing Internet Access</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/spacex-how-starlink-broadband-from-space-is-equalizing-internet-access/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/spacex-how-starlink-broadband-from-space-is-equalizing-internet-access/</guid><description>In this session, SpaceX presented how Starlink is already changing lives across the globe through access to high-quality broadband in the most rural and unserved areas. Connectivity is a foundation to improve communities and bridge the digital divide, and Starlink has already supported natural disaster recovery responses, education, healthcare, agriculture, and economic development use cases.
Spacelink and SWARM - a recent SpaceX acquisition that focuses on satellite connectivity for remote IoT devices - bring the technology solutions for connectivity no matter where in the world or what the project may be.</description></item><item><title>Unlock the Power of Geospatial Data with ESRI</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/unlock-the-power-of-geospatial-data-with-esri/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/unlock-the-power-of-geospatial-data-with-esri/</guid><description>In this session, our colleagues from ESRI presented use cases on environmental, economic, and social topics, and MF colleagues showcased how to visualize granular data with ArcGIS Online using Facebook&amp;rsquo;s Relative Wealth Index.</description></item><item><title>How We Can Harness the World’s Navigation Data in our Projects: Learning about Development Data Partner Mapbox</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/how-we-can-harness-the-world-s-navigation-data-in-our-projects-learning-about-development-data-partner-mapbox/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/how-we-can-harness-the-world-s-navigation-data-in-our-projects-learning-about-development-data-partner-mapbox/</guid><description>In this session, Mikel Maron, Michael Dussert, and Kieran Gupta from Mapbox presented what data products are available and how to use them and discussed their community resources.
Colleagues from the World Bank shared their projects using Mapbox data to optimize tourism investments in Sri Lanka, understand policies on road safety in Nairobi, and inform urban strategy in Costa Rica.</description></item><item><title>Measuring Green Jobs With LinkedIn Data</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/measuring-green-jobs-with-linkedin-data/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/measuring-green-jobs-with-linkedin-data/</guid><description>In this session, Karin Kimbrough, Chief Economist at LinkedIn, presented the new measures of green jobs profiles and possible use cases. LinkedIn&amp;rsquo;s team gave an overview of the available dataset and their applications.
The green jobs datasets are an extension of skill and jobs data currently available in the Partnership Portal - it offers measures of green skills, green talent, green jobs, green skills penetration, etc. The datasets are drawn from the anonymized and aggregated profile information of LinkedIn&amp;rsquo;s 770+ million members around the world.</description></item><item><title>Using Mobility Data In Your Projects with Outlogic</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/using-mobility-data-in-your-projects-with-outlogic/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/using-mobility-data-in-your-projects-with-outlogic/</guid><description>In this session, Outlogic discussed how mobility data is collected and presented use cases. Nick Jones shared GFDRR&amp;rsquo;s work on informing urban analytics through mobility data. Robert Marty from DIME showed how his team has been using mobile location data from Outlogic to evaluate transport projects.</description></item><item><title>Mapping Transportation Systems with WhereIsMyTransport</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/mapping-transportation-systems-with-whereismytransport/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/mapping-transportation-systems-with-whereismytransport/</guid><description>In this session, Yohnny Raich, Head of Data Product at WhereIsMyTransport (WIMT), discussed how WIMT collects data in emerging markets and presented the offerings via the Development Data Partnership. Fatima Arroyo-Arroyo, Senior Urban Transport Specialist at the World Bank, will discuss her project collecting and using WIMT data in Freetown, Sierra Leon.</description></item><item><title>Nowcasting Data with SpaceKnow</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/nowcasting-data-with-spaceknow/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/nowcasting-data-with-spaceknow/</guid><description>In this session, Anu Murgai (Vice President for Commercial Solutions), Jared Laxton (Applied Economist), and Jan Drabek (Delivery Engineer) from Spaceknow presented Spaceknow&amp;rsquo;s nowcasting data and discuss its use cases.</description></item><item><title>Learning About Atlas AI Data</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/learning-about-atlas-ai-data/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/learning-about-atlas-ai-data/</guid><description>During this workshop, Karen Byrnes and Shruti Jai will tell us more about Atlas AI and the datasets available through the Development Data Partnership. Our colleagues from the World Bank Development Data Group, Siobhan Murray, and Talip Kilic will share their experience working with Atlas AI in the 50X2030 Initiative.</description></item><item><title>University Data Fellows Projects</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/university-data-fellows-projects/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/university-data-fellows-projects/</guid><description>In this session, we learned about the University Data Fellows Program and our collaboration with students from the Cal Poly Digital Transformation Hub (DxHub). We also heard from World Bank colleagues who have worked together on projects about: Traceability of Cacao in Colombia - a collaboration with the Climate Change Fund Management Unit (SCCFM), and Simplifying the Identification of School Infrastructure Vulnerability at Scale - a collaboration with the Global Program for Safer Schools (GPSS).</description></item><item><title>Scaling Up Data Science With Dask</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/coiled-scaling-up-data-science-with-dask/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/coiled-scaling-up-data-science-with-dask/</guid><description>In this workshop, We discussed how Dask helps PyData users scale up their computations in exploratory data analysis, data engineering, and machine learning workflows. We also talked about challenges when scaling up to a cluster in terms of networking, performance tuning, package management, and data access. Finally, we walked through a number of interesting use cases with Dask, including an end-to-end workflow with geospatial data.</description></item><item><title>Facebook's Covid-19 Global Symptoms Survey</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/facebook-s-covid-19-global-symptoms-survey/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/facebook-s-covid-19-global-symptoms-survey/</guid><description>Through the Data for Good program, Facebook receives over a million weekly survey responses from users worldwide on COVID-19 topics such as symptoms, behaviors, and vaccine sentiment.
In this workshop with Kelsey Mulcahy from Facebook&amp;rsquo;s Data for Good team and Stefani Guevara from the Development Data Partnership team to look at the findings from Facebook&amp;rsquo;s vaccine hesitancy datasets and learn more about using COVID-19 survey data in your projects.</description></item><item><title>Session 2: Infectious Disease Catalogs And Risk Assessment</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/session-2-infectious-disease-catalogs-and-risk-assessment/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/session-2-infectious-disease-catalogs-and-risk-assessment/</guid><description>The purpose of this session is to have a technical overview of the infectious disease catalogs and risk assessment tools. The session covers a historical data overview including, data structure and format, event-level summary, temporal and spatial granularity, and common analyses Furthermore, the session will explain the modeled catalog overview including data structure and format, metadata and data dictionary, temporal data, demographic data, and common analyses.</description></item><item><title>Session 1: Infectious Disease Catalogs And Risk Assessment</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/infectious-disease-catalogs-and-risk-assessment/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/infectious-disease-catalogs-and-risk-assessment/</guid><description>The purpose of this workshop is to introduce infectious disease event catalogs, which are empirical and simulation-derived datasets that can be used to estimate the frequency and severity of past and potential future infectious disease epidemics and pandemics. While event catalogs are widely used in the insurance and actuarial fields and in the study of natural hazards, only recently have the techniques used to create such datasets have been applied to the study of infectious disease, or to associated development challenges.</description></item><item><title>Facebook's Relative Wealth Index</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/facebook-s-relative-wealth-index/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/facebook-s-relative-wealth-index/</guid><description>In this session, Alex Pompe from Facebook Data for Good Team presents the &amp;ldquo;The Relative Wealth Index.&amp;rdquo; The dataset predicts the relative standard of living within countries using de-identified connectivity data, satellite imagery, and other nontraditional data sources.</description></item><item><title>Learning about Where Is My Transport's Mobility Data</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/learning-about-where-is-my-transport-s-mobility-data/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/learning-about-where-is-my-transport-s-mobility-data/</guid><description>In this session, Yhonny Raich from WhereIsMyTransport (WIMT) shares how the company is mapping transportation systems around the world by digitalizing network information from every public transport mode, of every operational style, in emerging-market megacities. WIMT has worked in Africa, Latin America, Southeast Europe, and South and Southeast Asia, using a suite of custom tools for collecting and processing mobility data, and following a project management methodology that supports rapid and effective data production.</description></item><item><title>Facebook Data Sources for Projects</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/facebook-data-sources-for-projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/facebook-data-sources-for-projects/</guid><description>In this session, Alex Pompe and Omari Sefu from Facebook present the datasets available to World Bank staff, and Sreelakshmi Papineni from the Bank&amp;rsquo;s Africa Gender Innovation Lab explains how her team has been using Facebook&amp;rsquo;s Gender at Home and Future of Business Surveys to inform World Bank&amp;rsquo;s projects.</description></item><item><title>Google: Covid-19 Open-Data</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/google-covid-19-open-data/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/google-covid-19-open-data/</guid><description>In this session, Oscar Wahltinez and Aurora Cheung from Google&amp;rsquo;s Covid-19 Open-Data team present the largest Covid-19 epidemiological database available in addition to a powerful set of expansive covariates. The dataset includes open-sourced data with a permissive license (enabling commercial use) relating to vaccinations, epidemiology, hospitalizations, demographics, economy, geography, health, mobility, government response, weather, and more. Moreover, the data merge daily time-series from hundreds of data sources at a fine spatial resolution, containing over 20,000 locations and using a consistent set of region keys.</description></item><item><title>Working with Big Data in Databricks</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/working-with-big-data-in-databricks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/working-with-big-data-in-databricks/</guid><description>In this session, Kartheek Kandikuppa (World Bank ITS) and Maksim Pecherskiy (World Bank DEC Analytics &amp;amp; Tools) share what we need to know before we start working with Databricks.</description></item><item><title>Learn to Use Linkedin Data in Your Projects</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/learn-to-use-linkedin-data-in-your-projects/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/learn-to-use-linkedin-data-in-your-projects/</guid><description>LinkedIn is the world’s largest professional network, with more than 740 million members, 14 million jobs, and 5 million companies across 200 countries and territories around the world.
During the event, join our LinkedIn colleagues to learn about the LinkedIn data available through the Partnership, see case studies of its use in peer institutions, and discuss its application to projects as part of the Development Data Partnership.</description></item><item><title>SDG Atlas 2020 Behind-the-Scenes – From Raw Data to 17 Interactive Data Stories</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/sdg-atlas-2020-behind-the-scenes-from-raw-data-to-17-interactive-data-stories/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/sdg-atlas-2020-behind-the-scenes-from-raw-data-to-17-interactive-data-stories/</guid><description>During this event our DEC colleagues, Florina Pirlea and Divyanshi Wadhwa, lead core members of the SDG Atlas team, will give an overview of the SDG Atlas and walk us through the process involved in the making of the Atlas, starting from ideation to the end product.
Following this, Maarten Lambrechts, a member of the data visualization team behind the SDG Atlas 2020, will share insights from the process and technology used to manage and build the Atlas.</description></item><item><title>Big Data for Broadband Coverage and Economic Impact Assessment - Case of Ukraine</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/big-data-for-broadband-coverage-and-economic-impact-assessment-case-of-ukraine/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/big-data-for-broadband-coverage-and-economic-impact-assessment-case-of-ukraine/</guid><description>During the workshop, our Digital Development GP colleagues will share their work on broadband coverage and economic impact assessment conducted in Ukraine through merging multiple private and public data sources such as Ookla data on speed tests and Government’s data on penetration rates. The sessions will cover various aspects such as comparability and compatibility of data, data visualization, and catching anomalies.</description></item><item><title>Learn to Use Mapillary in Bank Projects</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/learn-to-use-mapillary-in-bank-projects/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/learn-to-use-mapillary-in-bank-projects/</guid><description>Edoardo Neerhut and Christopher Beddow from Mapillary will tell us about the resources and features available to the World Bank staff through the Development Data Partnership. They will also talk about Mapillary’s applications for road surveys and assessment, as well as disaster risk reductions, and OpenStreetMap integrations. And our colleague, Sarah Antos will tell us how her team has been using Mapillary in their projects.</description></item><item><title>How to Start Working with Private-Sector Data</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/development-data-partnership-how-to-start-working-with-private-sector-data/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/development-data-partnership-how-to-start-working-with-private-sector-data/</guid><description>Learn how to work with private sector data available through the Development Data Partnership. This session will cover: how to explore data partners and data opportunities, how to submit a proposal, where to find data documentation, code snippets, and data schemas, and more.</description></item><item><title>Data Partner Workshop Climacell</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/data-partner-workshop-climacell/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 07:31:44 -0400</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/data-partner-workshop-climacell/</guid><description>Climacell combines traditional weather sensor data with non-traditional sources to derive up-to-the minute, real time micro weather and air quality mapping and forecasts. There service is used primarily by utilities and transportation companies, like Uber and Ford, and airlines, such as JetBlue, United, and Delta. The workshop focused on the Bank&amp;rsquo;s response to the locust crisis in east Africa as a case study, but discussion and questions covered all manner of challenges &amp;ndash; transport, agriculture, industry, etc.</description></item><item><title>Esa Earth Observation Clinic</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/esa-earth-observation-clinic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 19:30:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/esa-earth-observation-clinic/</guid><description>The European Space Agency (ESA) supports on-call, prequalified geospatial firms ready to support your project on all manner of satellite-imagery and remote sensing activities. Support, valued at &amp;lt;= US$45,000, will be provided to qualified applicants. Apply through the Development Data Partnership (datapartnership.org).</description></item><item><title>Center for Open Science</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/center-for-open-science/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 19:30:10 -0400</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/center-for-open-science/</guid><description>Dr. Soderberg discussed the challenges and opportunities of Open Science and how the Center for Open Science is providing training and guidance to organizations on data sharing/reuse, and adding rigor to data analysis.</description></item><item><title>GIS and COVID-19: How Mapping Supports Response and Recovery</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/gis-and-covid19-how-mapping-supports-response-and-recovery/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 18:50:15 -0400</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/gis-and-covid19-how-mapping-supports-response-and-recovery/</guid><description>In this evelopment Data Partnership event, participants learn how IDB, UNICEF, and the WHO are using ESRI GIS technology to supporting COVID-19 response and recovery.</description></item><item><title>Learn How to Use Twitter Data In Bank Projects</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/learn-how-to-use-twitter-data-in-bank-projects/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 18:50:15 -0400</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/learn-how-to-use-twitter-data-in-bank-projects/</guid><description>Through the Development Data Partnership, World Bank staff have free access to Twitter’s Enterprise API platform, which offers real-time and historical social data. During this workshop, Twitter staff helped staff get started.</description></item><item><title>Facebook Data for Good Workshop</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/facebook-data-for-good-workshop/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 14:44:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/facebook-data-for-good-workshop/</guid><description>Through the Development Data Partnership with Facebook, staff can now access anonymized Facebook data products. Facebook colleagues introduced these new resources, and staff who have been using them presented their work on gender, energy, and disaster risk management projects.</description></item><item><title>Mapping and Analyzing Geospatial Data for Social Assistance Delivery</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/mapping-and-analyzing-geospatial-data-for-social-assistance-delivery/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 08:02:13 -0400</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/mapping-and-analyzing-geospatial-data-for-social-assistance-delivery/</guid><description>Learn how the team used geospatial data to improve the delivery of social assistance programs in Tunisia. The event is jointly organized by Social Protection &amp;amp; Jobs Global Practice, ITS Technology and Innovation Lab, and the WB Data Lab as part of the LearnDTech Initiative.</description></item><item><title>Measuring Equitable Access to Health Facilities with Data Partnerships and Open-Source Tools</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/measuring-equitable-access-to-health-facilities/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 08:00:22 -0400</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/measuring-equitable-access-to-health-facilities/</guid><description>Meet our summer intern Afeefah Khazi-Syed, biological engineering major at MIT, as she presents her research on analyzing physical access to health facilities. She hopes her work can inform decisions on how to allocate scarce resources towards placement of mobile health services. Afeefah&amp;rsquo;s work, which includes open-source code that Bank staff can use to replicate her results, utilizes data from Facebook and MapBox, acquired through the Development Data Partnership (datapartnership.org).</description></item><item><title>Data Science Talk: Learn How to Use Crowdsourced Smartphone GPS Data on your Project</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/data-science-talk-learn-how-to-use-crowdsourced-smartphone-gps-data/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 07:57:33 -0400</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/data-science-talk-learn-how-to-use-crowdsourced-smartphone-gps-data/</guid><description>The Development Data Partnership has partnered with four mobility data providers to acquire smartphone GPS data across many emerging economies. These data have applications for understanding population movement during the pandemic, supporting client advisory on topics such as social distancing measures, placement of mobilie testing facilities, and estimating economic activity. At the workshop, participants learned about these data providers, the data transformations undertaken by the Partnership team to make analytics easier, the data documentation system, and recent work on COVID-19 indicators.</description></item><item><title>Data Science Talk: Using Social Media Online News and Text Analysis for Monitoring COVID-19 Impacts</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/data-science-talk-using-social-media-online-news-and-text-analysis/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 19:38:43 -0400</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/data-science-talk-using-social-media-online-news-and-text-analysis/</guid><description>A Social Development GP team used alternative data (Twitter, Instagram, news media, Facebook, Google, Premise, etc.) to boost their COVID-19 social impact monitoring. Their work helped rapidly inform decision makers and identify rising public concerns, with a large population sample at a very low cost. Talk topics includesed: monitoring conversations via social media and online news; crowdsourcing citizen information via online surveys; comparing results across different data collection efforts; and integrating with other big data efforts, such as mobility analytics.</description></item><item><title>Data Science Talk: Monitoring Sentiment Towards COVID 19 Policies Using GDELT</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/data-science-talk-monitoring-sentiment-towards-covid-19-policies-using-gdelt/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 19:30:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/data-science-talk-monitoring-sentiment-towards-covid-19-policies-using-gdelt/</guid><description>GDELT, an open-licesne repository of real time local news data, is being used to track sentiment towards COVID-19 policies and challenges. The program&amp;rsquo;s founder, Kalev Leetrau, introduces how to access the many resources avaialble through the platform.</description></item><item><title>Data Partner Workshop: Ookla</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/data-partner-workshop-ookla/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 19:36:58 -0400</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/data-partner-workshop-ookla/</guid><description>Ookla, part of the Development Data Partnership, is one of the world&amp;rsquo;s largest providers of global Internet connectivity intelligence data. The workshop started with an introduction to the Ookla platofrm and was followed by a clinic with three Bank team who had submitted proposals to work with Ookla data.</description></item><item><title>Data Partner Workshop: Indigo</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/data-partner-workshop-indigo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 19:30:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/data-partner-workshop-indigo/</guid><description>We are very excited to introduce our newest Development Data Partnership member, Indigo. Through Indigo&amp;rsquo;s Atlas platform, users can access high-resolution, real-time data on crop location and health, impact of weather on crops, and more. During this introductory workshop, we learned about and discussed how we can make the most of this new platform.</description></item><item><title>US Digital Service Field Trip</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/us-digital-service-field-trip/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 07:18:57 -0400</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/us-digital-service-field-trip/</guid><description>Staff were treated to a presentation on how US federal government attracts talented mid-career tech talent to do a &amp;ldquo;tour of service&amp;rdquo; to help modernize public services, followed by a visit to the US Digital Service office, across from the White House.</description></item><item><title>Amazon Web Services Training</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/amazon-web-services/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 13:03:56 -0400</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/amazon-web-services/</guid><description>Amazon Web Services (AWS) training is part of a series of events organized by Development Data Partnership for IT staff and data scientists. The course covered new Amazon tools to make it easier and faster to organize and analyze very large, unstructured data. Training materials include self-paced, step-by-step hands-on lab activities. To access lab materials, please request permission from datalab@worldbank.org to access via GitHub.</description></item></channel></rss>