<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Lab Leads Meeting on World Bank Data Lab</title><link>/workshop_types/lab-leads-meeting/</link><description>Recent content in Lab Leads Meeting on World Bank Data Lab</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 01:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/workshop_types/lab-leads-meeting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>December 2022: Data Lab Leads Meeting</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/december-2022-data-lab-leads-meeting/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/december-2022-data-lab-leads-meeting/</guid><description>Join us for the Data Lab’s December meeting, where our Lab Leads from the ITS Technology and Innovation Lab will present their approach to exploring AI technologies and AI Projects with WBG Corporate &amp;amp; Operations.
in-person: World Bank Group Library virtual:Webex</description></item><item><title>October 2022: Data Lab Leads Meeting</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/october-2022-data-lab-leads-meeting/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/october-2022-data-lab-leads-meeting/</guid><description>In this session, Lab Lead Rochelle O&amp;rsquo;Hagan (DECIS) showed us the Development Data Hub (DDH) - the Bank&amp;rsquo;s official one-stop shop for the latest development data. Lab Lead Minh Cong Nguyen (EMNPV) and Tony Jany Fujs (DECIS) presented The Poverty and Inequality Platform (PIP), which offers quick access to the WB&amp;rsquo;s estimates of poverty, inequality, and shared prosperity.</description></item><item><title>September 2022: Data Lab Leads Meeting</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/september-2022-data-lab-leads-meeting/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/september-2022-data-lab-leads-meeting/</guid><description>In this session, DIME Lab Lead Maria Jones shared her team&amp;rsquo;s truly excellent data science reproducibility best practices, including their peer code review process and reproducibility checks. And, Gabriel Stefanini Vicente (DECAT) walked us through the new Data Lab GitHub-based data documentation templates, covering all sorts of cool tricks, including GitHub pages and actions.</description></item><item><title>May 2022: Data Lab Leads Meeting</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/may-2022-data-lab-leads-meeting/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/may-2022-data-lab-leads-meeting/</guid><description>In this session, the Data Lab presented foundational datasets curated to support Ukraine&amp;rsquo;s response efforts. DIME Lab Lead Maria Jones shared an overview of DIME Analytics, including the services and public resources offered to Bank staff. Environment Lab Lead Nagaraja Rao Harshadeep (Harsh) introduced the sustainable development data resources and services available to Bank staff through the Knowledge, Information &amp;amp; Data Services (KIDS) Helpdesk.</description></item><item><title>April 2022: Data Lab Leads Meeting</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/april-2022-data-lab-leads-meeting/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/april-2022-data-lab-leads-meeting/</guid><description>In this session, the Data Corps presented their approach to creating and managing data products that support coordinated Ukraine esponse efforts. Lab Leads Esha Zaveri and Pascal Saura presented the Water Data Portal, a source for water-related open data, including datasets and applications generated or compiled by the Water GP. C. MacKenzie Dove walked us through the Climate Change Knowledge Portal, a hub for climate-related information, data, and tools.</description></item><item><title>March 2022: Data Lab Leads Meeting</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/march-2022-data-lab-leads-meeting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/march-2022-data-lab-leads-meeting/</guid><description>In this session, Carlos Sabatino (EAEPV) shared datasets and resources available from the Poverty Global Practice. Lab Leads Sarah Bunker(HGNDR), and Heather G. Moylan (HGNDR) presented the new Gender Data Portal. Finally, Gabriel Stefanini Vicente showed his work-in-progress leveraging mobile location data.</description></item><item><title>February 2022: Data Lab Leads Meeting</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/february-2022-data-lab-leads-meeting/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/february-2022-data-lab-leads-meeting/</guid><description>In this session, our colleagues from the ITS shared the resources and services available for staff. Manar Eliriqsousi presented the RAD Data Analytics and Visualizations services, and Dany S. Jones showcased the GeoLab&amp;rsquo;s offerings and support areas.</description></item><item><title>January 2022: Data Lab Leads Meeting</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/january-2022-data-lab-leads-meeting/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/january-2022-data-lab-leads-meeting/</guid><description>In this session, our colleagues from the Infrastructure Vice-Presidency presented the new Global Infrastructure Dashboard. Our ITS Technology and Innovation Lab colleagues shared their research on data-driven Web 3.0 technologies.</description></item><item><title>November 2021: Data Lab Leads Meeting</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/november-2021-data-lab-leads-meeting/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2021 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/november-2021-data-lab-leads-meeting/</guid><description>In this session, our colleagues from the ITS Technology &amp;amp; Innovation Lab shared their latest projects and resources, as well as their collaboration with the Korea Country Office. Gabriel Stefanini Vicente (DECAT) walked us through best practices and tips for creating data documentation, and the Development Data Partnership team shared the latest catalog of datasets available from Facebook.</description></item><item><title>November 2022: Data Lab Leads Meeting</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/november-2022-data-lab-leads-meeting/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2021 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/november-2022-data-lab-leads-meeting/</guid><description>In this session, Ravi Kumar (DECSR) presented the Data Use and Literacy Program, which delivers various activities to build data literacy and data use capacity. Holly Krambeck (Data Lab) shared a proposal to create a Heatwaves Data Collaborative.</description></item><item><title>October 2021: Data Lab Leads Meeting</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/october-2021-data-lab-leads-meeting/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/october-2021-data-lab-leads-meeting/</guid><description>In this session, Andres Chamorro (DECAT) showed how the Global Operations Support Team (GOST) is expanding its geospatial services to include data science support, and Annabelle Vinois (GEMS) presented the latest Geo-Enabling Initiative for Monitoring and Supervision (GEMS) staff resources and initiatives. And, Aivin Vicquierra Solatorio (DECAT) walked us through his team&amp;rsquo;s innovative Natural Language Processing products, which will be foundational to supporting governments digitizing their records for the first time.</description></item><item><title>September 2021: Data Lab Leads Meeting</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/september-2021-data-lab-leads-meeting/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/september-2021-data-lab-leads-meeting/</guid><description>In this meeting, Rochelle O&amp;rsquo;Hagan from the Development Economics Data Group presented the Development Data Hub 2.0. Natalie Magee ​from the World Food Programme introduced the WFP Innovation Champions Community. And our colleagues from the Human Development Disruptive Tech Initiative​ sought advice for the Digital Toolkit for Human Development.</description></item><item><title>July 2021: Data Lab Leads Meeting</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/july-2021-data-lab-leads-meeting/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/july-2021-data-lab-leads-meeting/</guid><description>In this meeting, Duncan Omole and Elena Maslyukova from the WBG Library presented the latest data resources available for Bank projects. Nick Jones from GFDRR, and Gaurav Bhardwaj from DECIS introduced a Python for Data Science training course delivered to WB staff and RAS clients. Finally, Holly Kramberk from DECDG pitched the new Data Corps and Data Goods Programs.</description></item><item><title>June 2021: Data Lab Leads Meeting</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/june-2021-data-lab-leads-meeting/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/june-2021-data-lab-leads-meeting/</guid><description>In this meeting, we welcomed our Data Lab Leads for the FY22. Haishan Fu, Director of Development Data Group (DECDG) provided opening remarks, and colleagues from the Data Lab team gave an overview of the Lab&amp;rsquo;s activities and Lab Lead&amp;rsquo;s role.</description></item><item><title>January 2021: Data Lab Leads Meeting</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/january-2021-data-lab-leads-meeting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/january-2021-data-lab-leads-meeting/</guid><description>We kicked off the Data Lab Leads 2021 meeting series by inviting guest speaker and fellow colleague Joy Aoun to our first board meeting of the new year in January. Joy has been innovating up a storm on finding ways to quickly inform damage and needs assessments in places that are difficult to reach. Drawing upon social media, news, remote sensing, and other sources, her team has developed methods that may help improve regular project supervision.</description></item><item><title>November 2020: Data Lab Leads Meeting</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/november-2020-data-lab-leads-meeting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/november-2020-data-lab-leads-meeting/</guid><description>In this meeting, Riccardo de Marchi Trevisan and Calvin Kwon from ESRI presented ESRI Living Atlas and show us the geospatial tools available for bank staff. The team behind the SDG Atlas 2020 Data Visualizations also presented their insights and details about their work.</description></item><item><title>October 2020: Data Lab Leads Meeting</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/october-2020-data-lab-leads-meeting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2020 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/october-2020-data-lab-leads-meeting/</guid><description>In this meeting, our colleague Dixi Mengote-Quah presented the work of the SD Remote Sensing Working Group. This was followed by a presentation of the resources and datasets available to work on COVID-19 related projects. Finally, Lab Leads discussed the concept note preview for World Bank Data Lab.</description></item><item><title>September 2020: Data Lab Leads Meeting</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/september-2020-data-lab-leads-meeting-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/september-2020-data-lab-leads-meeting-1/</guid><description>In this meeting, the roadmap from the Data Lab was presented including what&amp;rsquo;s coming, the organization and structure as well as the round-up of Year 1 activities. Lab Leads also discussed the transition from SD to a World Bank DataLab.</description></item><item><title>May 2020: Data Lab Leads Meeting</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/may-2020-data-lab-leads-meeting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/may-2020-data-lab-leads-meeting/</guid><description>In this meeting, the Development Data Partnership team presented the mobile location data inventory. This was followed by an Introduction to remote supervision technology initiative.</description></item><item><title>April 2020: Data Lab Leads Meeting</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/april-2020-data-lab-leads-meeting/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/april-2020-data-lab-leads-meeting/</guid><description>In this meeting, we hosted a special clinic for the health global practice on COVID-19 location-based indicators. We had Bill Hoffman (World Economic Forum), Javier de la Torre (Carto), Alex Pompe (Facebook), Mikel Maron (MapBox), Bo Young Park, and Charlotte Stanton (Google), and Kalev Leetrau (GDELT) present solutions to address the problem, followed by a Round Robin of World Bank colleagues presenting their solutions.</description></item><item><title>March 2020: Data Lab Leads Meeting</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/march-2020-data-lab-leads-meeting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/march-2020-data-lab-leads-meeting/</guid><description>In this meeting, we had a lightning talk from our colleagues at DIME who presented their work and projects. This was followed by a clinic for the team of ProBlue, which was seeking advisory on digital innovation in ocean space.</description></item><item><title>February 2020: Data Lab Leads Meeting</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/february-2020-data-lab-leads-meeting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/february-2020-data-lab-leads-meeting/</guid><description>In this meeting, we learned about the WBG Library and the resources available to staff. This was followed by an overview of the Lab&amp;rsquo;s Who-Does-What directory.</description></item><item><title>January 2020: Data Lab Leads Meeting</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/january-2020-data-lab-leads-meeting/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/january-2020-data-lab-leads-meeting/</guid><description>In this meeting, we learned about the Ag Observatory including an overview of its work and support to the Bank. This was followed by a lightning talk from our colleagues working with LSMS (Living Standards Measurement Study).</description></item><item><title>November 2019: Data Lab Leads Meeting</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/november-2019-data-lab-leads-meeting/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/november-2019-data-lab-leads-meeting/</guid><description>In this meeting, our colleagues at GEMS (Geo-Enabling Initiative for Monitoring and Supervision) presented their work and how they are supporting the Bank&amp;rsquo;s work. This was followed by a presentation of the GFDRR Lab where we learned about their projects and the use of diverse technologies.</description></item><item><title>October 2019: Data Lab Leads Meeting</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/october-2019-data-lab-leads-meeting/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/october-2019-data-lab-leads-meeting/</guid><description>In this meeting, we learned about the ITS Tech &amp;amp; Innovation Lab&amp;rsquo;s work and its role in the Lab. Our colleagues from Disruptive KIDS (Knowledge, Information, and Data Science) also presented their work, and we went through the Lab Lead Survey Results and the Lab Lead Connector Role.</description></item><item><title>September 2019: Data Lab Leads Meeting</title><link>/workshops-and-clinics/september-2020-data-lab-leads-meeting/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workshops-and-clinics/september-2020-data-lab-leads-meeting/</guid><description>In this meeting, we discussed the Data Lab work and the rationale for its creation, as well as the Lab Activities, Resources, and Lab Leads roles.</description></item></channel></rss>